6141 US HIGHWAY 287, WOODVILLE, TEXAS 75979 409.659.4310. ASHLEY122104@YAHOO.COM

CLINICAL NURSE CONSULTANT

QUALIFICATIONS PROFILE

Compassionate, patient-centered, and highly organized professional, offering extensive experience in nursing and nursing services. Equipped with excellent communication and interpersonal skills in collaborating seamlessly with all levels of individuals to deliver the best care and service to patients. Capable of maintaining positive professional demeanor in a diverse and fast-paced environment. Proficient with Microsoft Office Suite (Word, Excel, and Outlook), TouchMD, CareConnect, eClinicalWorks, and Meditab. Articulate communicator; conversant in Spanish.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

DOCUMENTATION REVIEW/IMPROVEMENT PATIENT CARE LIAISON AND RELATIONS SPECIALST

CASE MANAGEMENT/CARE COORDINATOR EVIDENCE BASED PRACTICE/IMPROVED OUTCOMES

STAFF TRAINING, SUPERVISION AND DEVELOPMENT

HEALTH ASSESSMENT AND EDUCATION

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

TEXAS HOME HEALTH, Accent Care | Lufkin, TX

Registered Nurse Case Manager

Aug 2015-Present

- Carry out continuous review of all aspects of patients on their caseload, such as the properly utilizing services, guaranteeing provision of continued skilled need, and tracking homebound status, assessing documentation of medical records, and maintaining interdisciplinary communication and discharge planning.
- Develops strategies to maximize medical outcomes in a cost-effective manner.
- Perform a complete physical assessment and health history of the patient.
- **⊆** Conduct an initial evaluation of patient and family to identify home care needs.
- Formulate a care plan to set goals based on nursing diagnosis and incorporate therapeutic, preventive, and rehabilitative nursing actions.
- Accomplish appropriate preventive rehabilitative nursing procedures; and administer medications and treatments as prescribed by the physician.
- Offer health care instruction to patients in alignment with the assessment and plan.
- Reassess patients within 24 hours after a change in condition or a discharge from an impatient setting.
- Handle the financial resources and eligibility under different third-party payer sources, Medicare, and medical.
- Supervise licensed vocational nurses (LVNs) and home health aides in compliance with Certified Hospital Admission Program (CHAP) standards and regulatory requirements.
- Implement the plan of care for patients and provide appropriate revisions in line with status and needs changes
- Performs assigned audits by researching documentation, analyzing information, and makes recommendations to improve flow of claim and enters all corrections into the systems
- Serves as charge master liaison to include regular reviews of CPT codes, Revenue Codes, review of monthly standard CDM error report

EVICORE HEALTHCARE | Bluffton, SC

Clinical Nurse Reviewer

Nov 2012-Aug 2015

- Evaluated monthly reports to ensure maintenance of department performance of daily production within established metric expectations.
- Assist with the development of new review tools as products are developed; screening and write-ups of external appeal review cases; following-up with patients, insurers and providers relative to the external appeal process; preparation of final report determinations for external appeals and tracking of cases to ensure timely response.
- Directed new clinical and support staff on daily productions.
- **■** Collaborated with appropriate departments to identify available resources.
- Managed clinical and utilization review to control costs while keeping track of quality of patient care.
- Evaluated electronic medical records by assessing the appropriateness of healthcare consumption. Experience in MCG and InterQual guidelines.
- Coordinated with patients, physicians, and insurance providers daily to guarantee effective case management.

WOODVILLE INDEPENDENT SCHOOL DISTRICT | Woodville, TX

Health Services Coordinator

Aug 2009-Nov 2012

ASHLEY BURKHALTER, RN

6141 US HIGHWAY 287, WOODVILLE, TEXAS 75979 409.659.4310. ASHLEY122104@YAHOO.COM

- Prioritized and focused on the prevention of sickness and disabilities and early detection and correction of health issues.
- Rendered complete health evaluation and determined any abnormal health findings.
- Performed mandated health screenings, physicals, and special education assessments.
- Created policies and procedures for crises interventions for acute illness, injury, and emotional disturbances.
- Handled school and community health services as the point of contact among the community, school, and home.
- Supported with the control of communicable diseases through preventative education programs, as well as early detection, surveillance, and reporting of contagious diseases.
- Maintained involvement with Child Education Evaluation Team to develop the health individualized education plan (IEP).

ADVANCED PEDIATRIC CARE | Beaumont, TX

Private Duty Pediatric Nurse

May 2007-Nov 2009

- Executed initial and ongoing health evaluations of individual patients and their families by assessing their physical, mental, and environmental status, subsequently conducting nursing interventions based on assessment of need.
- Utilized independent emergency measures to counteract adverse health developments while informing and alerting physicians regarding the condition of the patient.
- Observed patient health status by tracking and documenting vital signs, blood and urine laboratory values, intake and output, and heart and lung auscultation.
- Guaranteed appropriate documentation of patient care and regular communication with the patient, their family, care givers, and physician while instructing and leading the home attendants.

EDUCATION AND CREDENTIALS

Bachelor of Science in Nursing, In Progress (Expected Graduation Date: December 2018)

EXCELSIOR COLLEGE, Albany, NY

Associate of Science in Nursing - 2016

EXCELSIOR COLLEGE, Albany, NY

Licensed Vocational Nurse Program - 2006

TYLER COUNTY SCHOOL OF VOCATIONAL NURSING | Woodville, TX

Certifications

Certificate in Legal Nurse Consultant Program (2017), Vicki Malazzio Institute | Houston, TX Certificate in Youth Mental Health First Aide (2014), National Council for Community Behavior Healthcare | Washington, DC Certificate in First Aid Basic Life Support (BLS)/Cardiopulmonary Resuscitation (CPR), (2016) American Red Cross, TX

Training

Injectable and Advanced Injectable Medical Aesthetics Training (2018), National Laser Institute | Dallas, TX

AFFILIATIONS

Member, National Alliance of Certified Legal Nurse Consultants
Member, Woodville ISD Student Health Advisory Council (SHAC)
Volunteer Health Care Professional, American Red Cross
Member, Texas Association of Nurses
Member, American Nurses Association